so the notorious
rbg died yesterday
ruth bader ginsburg at the age of 87
died from complications with pancreatic
cancer
and the fact that she was basically
required to work through
cancer into her late 80s
she could have retired at the end of
obama's presidency and she didn't
probably because like the rest of us she
thought that hillary clinton was going
to get in
and that would have been really amazing
to be one of the supreme court justices
on the supreme court when the first
woman was a president right that would
as one of the very
this only the second female on the
supreme court having hillary be your
president would be pretty cool
and also if you're not ready to retire
you're not ready to retire
i think if she would have known that
trump was getting in she maybe would
have would have retired
but then she would have retired very
early in obama's presidency so he could
have appointed a a new supreme court
justice without what happened at the end
of his presidency when i don't remember
why there was a spot that was open
whether someone died or retired
but when there was that spot that was
open and there was a lot of
controversy whether he should appoint or
wait till the to the next president to a
point and i know they waited until the
next president
and then we got kavanagh when you look
at the difference between kavanaugh's
backstory and he was able to get on the
supreme court
versus her backstory her backstory i
mean it was
it she's she's died and so they're not
going to necessarily
dig up horrible things about her but i
guarantee you she wouldn't be on the
supreme court if she had horrible things
in her history
even like a rumor of it let alone
multiple women coming forward she went
to law school when there was very few
women who went out of a class of 500 she
was
one of nine women she went to school
with her husband her husband
went through cancer while they were in
law school they had a daughter so she
attended both of their classes looked
after her husband and their young
daughter
well to like being a lawyer and clearly
graduate at the top of her class
she couldn't find a job she ended up
becoming a teacher
that is like a superhero backstory
like to be able to do all of that you
have to have some superhuman vitality
some superhuman intelligence and she
clearly had her
her cognitive capabilities up until the
end my grandmother had her cognitive
capabilities up until 98. i remember
sitting in the
room table being like your brain's
better than my brain my brain's in its
30s
your brains in its 90s
but there's something so broken about
our current system that she was forced
to
to to be there up until when she she
until she died
that they're appointed for life
and although we're not necessarily going
to get a say
and i mean be the people i'm not really
not going to say as a canadian
on who the new appointment is
changing the law so they don't have a
lifetime appointment being able to
witness the law changes as they come
about to be able to
witness laws as they re-enacted and
understand them
and not have it be boring and on cnn on
some other channel or we can't
we're not witnessing it no one should
have to sit through that when they don't
enjoy
it but to be able to have something like
wikilection
which were one of the people and
together tech is creating
happens to be my brother an imbd type
thing for politicians and ceos and and
top um
people in business and politics and law
that when you're able to see a snapshot
of who somebody is
i don't think we get people like
kavanagh because you can't just spin it
the one percent own media can't just
spin it when you can see
see their their entire imbd right like
you can't just spin
who starred in a movie because you could
just google it in 30 seconds
you the same thing it's like wait we can
see how all these people are
interconnected working in these in these
the same corporation weird how you have
this lobbyist or this one used to work
for these people
there are ways that the people can truly
take back their power
without it necessarily being to just go
out and vote
going out and voting is an important
step when you have two
horrible options both of whom are
nowhere near as mentally there
as rbg is was was was she smaller
immensely there
24 hours later that
there is something that we can do
there are many things we can do if
voting every four years
is all you're capable of we need to at
least give you better choices
because the two choices on your bell at
this this time
are horrific they're both horrible
horrible horrible choices
and luckily it doesn't actually matter
who gets in what matters
is that the 99.9 of people
without money without power the 99 of
people
realize they do have power collectively
not just in their vote
but every day where you put your
attention
how we come together and organize this
information so it's usable
and understandable to the masses doesn't
mean everyone needs to use it and
understand it
but if it's there so we could
the media can't spin it in the same way
they currently can there are sense
making tools we can create
so that we can not just witness what is
happening in our higher courts
but have a direct impact on it
because when politicians when we can
truly watch politicians
in real time hold them accountable in
real time
in a way that can't be spun by the media
our entire political game changes the
only reason it happens the way it is
right now is because money's involved
and they can we have gold fish like
attention spans
no i got a goldfish like attention span
so rest in peace
rbg we got this
we will carry on your legacy we will
stand up for women
we will stand up for lgbt
and we will create a world that works
for everyone
which may not have been her dream but it
sure as hell is mine
and although i'm no way capable of going
to law school
and or getting married looking after a
husband looking after a kid
like one thing at a time for me
i do have this i know how to create a
world that works for everyone
and i'm actively participating in it and
i
invite you to do the same do what is
yours to do
come watch out if you're not already
subscribed subscribe
because what is coming out of this
channel
is going to save the world it's going to
change the world
not just this channel not just me but
all of the people that i'm connected
with
all of the people that can see what we
can do
together and are actively working
towards it
you're invited to be one of those people
thank you